<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pablo Dip</title>
    <link>https://pablodip.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pablo Dip</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2023, Dip Pablo</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 17:13:57 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pablodip.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Load Balancing and Failover using PCC on RouterOS</title>
      <link>https://pablodip.me/post/load-balancing-and-fail-over-using-pcc-on-routeros/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 15:17:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pablodip.me/post/load-balancing-and-fail-over-using-pcc-on-routeros/</guid>
      <description>Today, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to set up a failover-capable load balancer using the PCC (Per Connection Classifier) method, a highly flexible load balancing solution that is straightforward to configure. Since there are a lot of misconceptions about load balancing and the speeds you can achieve, let me clarify that it is not possible to split a network connection in half, route each half through different ISPs, and expect them to magically reunite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping an apex domain to an Azure CDN endpoint with automated SSL Certificate management</title>
      <link>https://pablodip.me/post/mapping-an-apex-domain-to-an-azure-cdn-endpoint-with-automated-ssl-certificate-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 11:11:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pablodip.me/post/mapping-an-apex-domain-to-an-azure-cdn-endpoint-with-automated-ssl-certificate-management/</guid>
      <description>Following up the theme of my previous article From Static to Stellar: Hosting Hugo sites in Azure Storage containers &amp;amp; Azure CDN, I will show you how to map a root domain to an Azure CDN endpoint.
At the time of this writing, Azure doesn&amp;rsquo;t support root domains using Azure CDN Managed certificates. The Azure documentation gives us two options to map the root domain, you can use your own certificate (stored in Azure Key vault) or you can purchase a new certificate through Key vault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Static to Stellar: Hosting Hugo sites in Azure Storage containers &amp; Azure CDN</title>
      <link>https://pablodip.me/post/hosting-hugo-sites-in-azure-storage-containers-and-azure-cdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 15:23:30 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pablodip.me/post/hosting-hugo-sites-in-azure-storage-containers-and-azure-cdn/</guid>
      <description>After publishing my article &amp;ldquo;Integrating a deployment counter to your CI/CD pipeline&amp;rdquo;, my static website recibed about 1.3k visits, not alot but it was enough to notice some performance issues.
To address this, I decided to transition from Azure Static Web Apps to a better setup using Azure Storage Containers and Azure Content Delivery Network (CDN).
In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;re diving into the world of hosting websites on Azure with the added benefit of Azure CDN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating a deployment counter to your CI/CD pipeline</title>
      <link>https://pablodip.me/post/deployment-counter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 16:16:39 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pablodip.me/post/deployment-counter/</guid>
      <description>I was reading a blog by Chad Carlson about Measuring Deployment Success with GitHub Actions and I noticed a stylish deployment counter featured at the bottom of their website, highlighting their platform&amp;rsquo;s successful deployments. While a PaaS provider like platform.sh will have many more deployments than my personal website, I felt inspired to create a similar counter and integrate it into my CI/CD pipeline.
For some context, my website is a static website built using hugo and hosted on Azure as a Static Web App.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encrypting External Storage for Enhanced Security</title>
      <link>https://pablodip.me/post/encrypted-external-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 14:55:04 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pablodip.me/post/encrypted-external-storage/</guid>
      <description>Protecting sensitive information from unauthorized access and potential breaches is crucial, especially when it comes to external storage devices like USB drives, which are susceptible to loss or theft.
After setting up an encrypted Proxmox instance on my server, I needed to protect my external storage. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be very usefull to run my hypervisor over an encrypted LVM volume if I store all my backups and data on a open HDD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing an encrypted Proxmox instance</title>
      <link>https://pablodip.me/post/encrypted-proxmox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 16:46:34 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pablodip.me/post/encrypted-proxmox/</guid>
      <description>Although Proxmox VE is a Debian-based Linux distribution, its installer doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer us the possibility of setting up an encrypted LVM. To install proxmox over an encrypted drive we need to install Debian 11 first, change the network configuration, and then install the proxmox packages.
Installing Debian 11 (Bullseye) Download Debian from the official website https://www.debian.org/download, along with the SHA512SUMS and the Signature.
Generate a checksum for the ISO file and save it: sha512sum debian-11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://pablodip.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 17:13:57 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pablodip.me/about/</guid>
      <description>About Hello 👋 I&amp;rsquo;m Pablo Dip. I live in Tucuman, Argentina
Contact You can reach me by email at pablodip@protonmail.com. You can also connect with me on LinkedIn and GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruteforcing a fully encrypted LVM drive</title>
      <link>https://pablodip.me/post/bruteforcing-luks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 16:16:39 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pablodip.me/post/bruteforcing-luks/</guid>
      <description>One of the most crucial lessons that security professionals and enthusiasts must grasp is that security policies should be tailored to a business&amp;rsquo;s needs, and realistic goals should be set for their implementation. I learned this lesson many years ago by forgetting the last 4 chars of my 45-character-long password.
Back in 2014, &amp;ldquo;No Place to Hide&amp;rdquo; by Glenn Greenwald had just come out, and the side effect of reading it in a couple of days is a bit of paranoia.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
